<resources>
    
    <string name="bench_press">Using a Barbell or Dumbbells,
        lie flat on the bench and keep feet flat on the floor.
        Lock your shoulders in and keep it outside shoulder width.
        Engage your glutes and core. Squeeze your chest to lift the weights.
        Take a deep breathe and proceed to bring the weight to chest level.
        Then bring the weight up to the starting position while exhaling. </string>

    <string name="chest_fly"> Using dumbbells and laying flat on the bench,
        start with your arms at your sides at chest level with your elbows slightly bent and pointing out.
        Lift your arms above your chest with the weights while exhaling then lower the arms to the starting position while inhaling.
        This can be done with the bench inclined to 30 degrees.</string>

    <string name="push_up"> Start with all fours on the ground and position your hands slightly wider from your shoulders.
        Keep elbows slightly bent and extend your legs back so you are balanced on your hands and toes with your feet being hip-width apart.
        Once positioned, lower yourself until your chest touches the ground, then push yourself up with your hands. </string>

    <string name="dips"> Grab parallel bars and hoist yourself up.
        Bend knees to keep stable and keep head straight by looking forward.
        Keep elbows locked in the side and lower yourself until your triceps are parallel to the floor.
        Push yourself back up to the starting position. </string>

    <string name="pullover"> Lying flat on the bench.
        Put both hands on one end of the dumbbell with the rest of the weight hanging vertically under your hands.
        Engage glutes and core and lift dumbbell directly above your chest.
        Keep arms straight as you lower the weight horizontally over your head.
        Reverse the movement to bring the weight back up overhead.
        Ensure that your pecs are flexing during the process. </string>

    <string name="sit_up"> Lay flat on the ground and bend the legs at a 90 degree angle.
    Keep feet flat on the ground for extra stability. Engage core and lift your torso up to the legs.
    Lay back onto the ground at a slower pace.
    Keep hands behind head for increased intensity.</string>
    
    <string name="burpee"> Start with a deep squat and hands on the ground with straightened arms.
        Kick both feet back to be on your hands and toes in a push up position.
        Lower until your chest touches the ground.
        Push back up until the arms are fully extended.
        Jump your legs back into the starting position.
        Jump vertically using your legs.
        Repeat the from the starting position.</string>

    <string name="plank"> Start with the elbows and toes on the ground.
        Ensure that the is aligned with the chest.
        Maintain a straight posture on the back.
        Hold this position for as long as you wish.</string>
    
    <string name="crunches"> Similar to the sit up. Lay flat on the ground and bend the legs at a 90 degree angle while keeping the feet flat on the ground.
        Instead of raising the whole torso, raise the upper torso while the core is engaged.
        Raise further until the abdomen is squeezed. 
        Once completed, lower the back to the ground and repeat the process. Keep hands behind back.
    </string>
    
    <string name="hollow_body_hold"> Lay on the ground with the upper back slightly off the ground.
    Raise arms vertically above the head to improve stability and raise the legs off the ground to activate the core.
    Hold this position for as long as needed.</string>
    
    <string name="barbell_squats"> Stand with your feet shoulder-width apart and the barbell resting on your upper traps.
    Keep chest up and back straight.
    Slowly lower your body by bending your knees and pushing your hips back.
    Lower until you are in a deep squat position. 
    Push through your heels to return to the standing position. </string>
    
    <string name="lunges"> Stand tall with your feet hip-width apart.
    Optionally, hold a pair of dumbbells at your sides for added intensity.
    Take a large step forward with one leg, bending both knees to lower your body until your front thigh is parallel to the ground and your rear knee is just above the floor.
    Push through your front heel to return to the starting position.</string>
    
    <string name="step_ups"> Find a sturdy platform that is around knee height.
    Optionally hold dumbbells, either in each hand or one in a goblet position.
    Step up onto the platform facing it and drive the heel on the platform to lift the other foot up.
    Lower yourself under control until you have stepped back down with your other foot.</string>

    <string name="pistol_squats"> Stand with your feet hip-width apart and extend one leg in front of you.
    lower the body down to squat position with one foot and drive through your heel to lift your body up.
    Ensure your back is straight and chest is up during the squat, ideally maintain balance too.
    Optionally, if the movement is too intense, hold onto something to keep the body stable and lighter. </string>

    <string name="walking_lunges"> Similar to lunges, lunge forward with one foot and lower until the front thigh is parallel to the ground.
    Once in the lunging position, push the heel in front forward to bring the other leg forward.
    Alternate both legs with each step. </string>
    
    <string name="dumbbell_lateral_raises">Stand tall and straight with both dumbbells on each hand by your sides, palms facing your body.
    Keep arms slightly bent and raise both dumbbells to your sides until they are parallel to the ground.
    Briefly pause at the top and slowly lower the dumbbells back down to the thighs.</string>

    <string name="dumbbell_shoulder_press"> Sit on a bench with back support, hold a dumbbell in each hand and position them so that they are level with your shoulders.
    Press dumbbells overhead until your arms are fully extended without locking the elbows.
    Slowly lower the arms back down to shoulder height. </string>

    <string name="dumbbell_front_raises">  Stand tall with dumbbells on each hand with the palms facing your thighs.
    Lift dumbbells directly in front of you until the arms are parallel from the ground.
    Lower it slowly back to the starting position.</string>
    
    <string name="dumbbell_rear_delt_flyes"> Bend forward at the hips with a dumbbell in each hand, palms facing each other.
    Slightly bend elbows as the dumbbells are raised. Raise out to the sides until both arms are parallel to the ground.
    Squeeze your shoulders together at the top of the movement, the slowly lower the dumbbells back down. </string>

    <string name="arnold_press"> Sitting on the bench with back support, hold a dumbbell in each hand at shoulder width with your palms facing the shoulders.
    Press the dumbbells overhead while rotating your palms to face forward.
    Once arms are fully extended, rotate your palms back to the shoulders while lowering the dumbbells slowly.</string>

    <string name="dumbbell_bicep_curls"> Stand tall with dumbbells on each hand, fully extend arms by your sides at a slight angle.
    Keep palms facing forward with the elbows and elbows close to the body, curl the dumbbells upward toward your shoulders while inhaling.
    Squeeze your bicep and fore arms at the top. Lower the dumbbells again to the starting position slowly while exhaling.</string>

    <string name="hammer_curl"> Stand tall with a dumbbell on each hand.
    Keep arms fully extended by your sides with the palms facing each other.
    Keep elbows close to the body, inhale as you curl the dumbbells upward toward your shoulders. Squeeze your biceps and forearms at the top.
    Slowly lower arms to the side again while exhaling.</string>

    <string name="alt_db_curl"> Similar to the dumbbell bicep curl, you curl to the shoulders and lower the dumbbell again.
    Instead of using both arms to curl, keep one stationary while one arm is curling. Once one arm has curled, use the other arm to curl.</string>

    <string name="preacher_curl"> Incline the bench at a slight angle, chest facing the bench while sitting.
    Position fully extended arms facing the ground and curl the dumbbells upward until the palms face the shoulders.
    Squeeze biceps and forearms then slowly lower the dumbbells to the starting position. Ensure elbows are not moving.</string>

    <string name="incline_db_curl"> Set at an adjustable bench to a 45-degree angle. Sit on the bench with dumbbells on each hand, arms fully extended towards the floor, palms facing forward.
    Keep upper arms stationary, inhale as you curl the dumbbells upward towards the shoulders, exhale while lowering the dumbbells back down to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="pull_up"> Stand underneath a an overhead horizontal bar that can support body weight.
    Drip the bar with your hands, ensure they are shoulder-width apart, make sure palms are either with facing forward or towards you.
    Engage your core to keep body stabilised and pull yourself upwards, inhale on your way up. When the shoulders are level with your hands, lower yourself under control to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="bent_over_row"> Stand with your feet shoulder-width apart, holding a dumbbell in each hand with your palms facing the body.
        Bend at the waist until the chest is parallel to the floor and knees are slightly bent.
        Inhale as you pull the dumbbells up towards your rib cage, keeping the elbows close to your body.
        Exhale as you lower the dumbbells back to the starting position.
    </string>

    <string name="renegade_rows"> In a plank position. fully extend the arms with dumbbells on each hand.
        Align wrists with shoulders, engage your core and keep your body in a straight line.
        Inhale as you row one dumbbell towards your rib-cage, ensure your hips do not move.
        Exhale as you lower the dumbbell to the starting position.
        Alternate with the other dumbbell on the other side.
    </string>

    <string name="dumbbell_shrugs"> Stand tall with dumbbells on both hands, arms fully extended, both palms facing the body.
    Inhale as you shrug your shoulders upwards towards your ears, squeezing the upper traps at the top of the movement.
    Exhale as you lower your shoulders to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="deadlifts"> Stand with your feet hip-width apart, toes pointing forward, Grip the barbell or dumbbells with your hands shoulder-width apart.
    Bend hips and lower yourself down, make sure the back is kept straight and chest up.
    Drive through the heels to lift the weight, ensure chest is up and core engaged to the point where the arms are fully extended.
    Once the body is straight and that the weights are level with the hips. Bring the wright back down towards the floor, if using the barbells, ensure it is touching the floor, and if you are using dumbbells, make sure they are positioned below the knees. </string>

    <string name="supermans"> Lie face down on the ground with both arms extended overhead and your legs straight.
    Engage the lower back and glutes as you lift your arms.
    Chest and legs must stay off the ground simultaneously.
    Hold the top position for a few seconds and lower back down with control.</string>

    <string name="good_mornings"> Stand tall with a barbell on your traps, engage your core and keep the back straight. Hinge at your hips to lean forward and lower the chest until it is parallel to the ground.
    Ensure your knees are bent slightly during the movement. drive the heels forward to return to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="glute_bridges"> Lie on your back with bent knees and feet flat at hip-width apart.
    Engage core and glutes as you lift your hips towards the ceiling. Squeeze your glutes at the top of the movement, then slowly lower your hips back down to the starting position.
    Optionally, place a barbell on your hips to add more weight and intensity to the movement.</string>

    <string name="side_leg_raises"> Lie on your side with your legs straight and stacked on top of each other.
        Support your upper body by holding onto something and keep your head aligned with your spine.
        Engage your core and lift with your top leg toward the ceiling as high as you can without rotating your hips.
        Hold the top position briefly, then lower your leg back down under control. To add more resistance and intensity, attach a resistance band on your heels then carry on with the movement.
    </string>

    <string name="clamshells"> Lie on your side with your hips and knees bent, head resting on your bottom arm.
    Keep your feet together and lift your top knee as high as you can while keeping your feet in contact with each other.
    Hold the top position briefly, then lower your knee back down with control.</string>

    <string name="romanian_deadlifts"> Stand with your feet hip-width apart, knees slightly bent and hold a barbell or a pair of dumbbells on both hands.
        Palms should face the thighs. Engage your core and keep your back straight and chest up, hinge the hips to lower the weight towards the ground until you feel a stretch in your hamstrings.
        Drive through the heels and extend your hips to return to the starting position, squeezing the glutes at the top.
    </string>

    <string name="hamstring_curls"> Attach a resistance band above the foot, turn the body so the chest faces the ground and lie flat on the ground with the whole body straight.
    keep glutes engaged as you curl the feet towards the glutes, contracting your hamstrings. Slowly lower the feet to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="nordic_holds"> Secure your feet so that it is under a foot plate, or have someone hold your ankles.
    Keep torso straight with chest up and engage glutes and core. lean the torso forward until you feel a contraction in the hamstrings.
    Lift the body back to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="jump_rope"> Hold a jump rope in both hands with your palms facing forward.
    Jump off the ground with both feet simultaneously using your calves to propel yourself off the ground.
    while your jumping, make sure the swinging jump rope slips through your feet.
    Once you land softly on the top of your feet. propel yourself off the ground once again to repeat the movement.</string>

    <string name="calf_raises"> stand with the feet on the edge of a step with the heels hanging off the edge. slowly elevate you heels as high as you possibly can lift it.
    pause at the top and lower your heels back down below the level of the step to stretch your calves.</string>

    <string name="skull_crushers"> Lie on the flat bench with either a dumbbell on each hand with palms facing each other or a barbell with the palms facing forward.
    Extend the arms out fully and inhale as you slowly lower the dumbbells/barbells.
    the weight must be above your forehead by bending your elbows, keep upper arms stationary.
    exhale as you bring the weight up to the starting position.</string>

    <string name="close_grip_bench_press"> Lie flat on the bench and grasp the barbell with your hands positioned closer than shoulder-width apart.
    Inhale as you slowly bring the barbell towards your chest, pause briefly and bring the barbell back up to the starting position.</string>


</resources>