<resources>
    
    <string name="bench_press">Using a Barbell or Dumbbells,
        lie flat on the bench and keep feet flat on the floor.
        Lock your shoulders in and keep it outside shoulder width.
        Engage your glutes and core. Squeeze your chest to lift the weights.
        Take a deep breathe and proceed to bring the weight to chest level.
        Then bring the weight up to the starting position while exhaling. </string>

    <string name="chest_fly"> Using dumbbells and laying flat on the bench,
        start with your arms at your sides at chest level with your elbows slightly bent and pointing out.
        Lift your arms above your chest with the weights while exhaling then lower the arms to the starting position while inhaling.
        This can be done with the bench inclined to 30 degrees.</string>

    <string name="push_up"> Start with all fours on the ground and position your hands slightly wider from your shoulders.
        Keep elbows slightly bent and extend your legs back so you are balanced on your hands and toes with your feet being hip-width apart.
        Once positioned, lower yourself until your chest touches the ground, then push yourself up with your hands. </string>

    <string name="dips"> Grab parallel bars and hoist yourself up.
        Bend knees to keep stable and keep head straight by looking forward.
        Keep elbows locked in the side and lower yourself until your triceps are parallel to the floor.
        Push yourself back up to the starting position. </string>

    <string name="pullover"> Lying flat on the bench.
        Put both hands on one end of the dumbbell with the rest of the weight hanging vertically under your hands.
        Engage glutes and core and lift dumbbell directly above your chest.
        Keep arms straight as you lower the weight horizontally over your head.
        Reverse the movement to bring the weight back up overhead.
        Ensure that your pecs are flexing during the process. </string>


</resources>